Eric W. Lawson Arbitration Files 6366
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Eric W. Lawson Arbitration Files
1984-2016
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Lawson, Eric W.
American Arbitration Association (AAA)
Public Employment Relation Board (PERB)
6366
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Labor Arbitration Decisions.
This collection consists of over 180 New York State labor arbitration cases where Eric Lawson was either the sole arbitrator or a member of the arbitration panel.
8311163
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 23, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, May 26, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Eric W. Lawson, Jr. has been a labor arbitrator since the early 1980s with affliations with the National Academy of Arbitrators, the Industrial Relations Research Association (formerly president of the Western New York IRRA), the Association for Conflict Resolution (SPIDR charter member), the New York State Bar Association, and the Saratoga County Bar Association.
After working as a public employment mediator for the New York State Public Employment Relations Board (NYSPERB) from 1969 to 1979, Mr. Lawson earned a law degree from SUNY Buffalo. As a labor arbitrator Mr. Lawson has worked mainly out of Saratoga Springs, NY. He has remained active in arbitration well into 2013.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of over 180 New York State labor arbitration cases where Eric Lawson was either the sole arbitrator or a member of the arbitration panel. Most of the case were heard under the authority of the American Arbitration Association (AAA), the Disciplinary Panel Administration, the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), the New York State Public Employment Relations Board (PERB), or the New York State Education Department (SED). The bulk of the cases were decided from 2000 to 2013, though cases as early as 1984 are included. Most of the workers in these cases members of a few professions: teachers, law lnforcement officers, local government employees, and health care workers. The most common issues at stake in these cases are termination and disciplinary actions.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4095: Alice Grant Additional Records /4283: ILR School Extension Division (Buffalo, N.Y.) Files 5293: New York State Teachers Association Records
Broome County, New York; Chautauqua County, New York; Niagara County, New York; Saratoga County, New York; Steuben County, New York; Lawson, Eric W.; American Arbitration Association (AAA); New York State Public Employment Relations Board (PERB); New York State Department of Education (SED); Disciplinary Panel Administration; United Federation of Teachers (UFT); Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA); America Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME); Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMDS)
8311163
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 1984-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: State of New York, Office of Mental Health and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 1984; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    February 23, 1984. Case number: 1367 092 83. Consent Award regarding unknown grievance.
    Format: Arbitration Case.
  - Item 2: Superintendent of Schools, Savona Central School District and Savona Central Shool Faculty Association, 1990; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 1)
    November 9, 1990. Case number: 15 390 0415 KMZ. Opinion and Award regarding stipend allegedly owed.
  - Item 3: County of Chenago and The Chenango County Deputy Sheriffs' Association, 1992; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 1)
    October 14, 1992. Case number: 15 390 0186 91 LRC. Opinion and Award regarding discharge.
  - Item 4: City of Ithaca New York and Ithaca Paid Firefighters, 1993; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 1)
    February 20, 1993. Case number: 15 390 0317 91 LRC. Award and Application to Clarify Award regarding back pay or time credit.
  - Item 5: State of New York, State University of New York and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 1998; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 1)
    May 16, 1998. Motion to Dismiss regarding suspension.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Council 66, Local 400, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) and City of Syracuse New York, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 2)
    November 26, 2002. Case number: 15 390 00218 2. Opinion and Award regarding overtime.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Genesis Healthcare of New York Inc. and Local 721 Service Employees' International Union (SEIU), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 3)
    October 30, 2001. Case number: 15 300 00437 1. Opinion and Award regarding demotion and suspension. Genesis Healthcare doing business as Mercy Care of Northern New York.
  - Item 2: Broome County and Council 82, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 3)
    December 7, 2001. Case number: 15 390 00443 1. Opinion and Interim Award regarding leave accrual use.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Broome Community College, and the County of Broome, and Faculty Association of Broome Community College, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    April 13, 2002. Case number: 15390 00882 11. Opinion and Award regarding retrenchment.
  - Item 2: Champlain Valley Physicians Hospital Medical Center and Licensed Practical Nurses, Technicians and Health Care Workers of New York, Local 721, SEIU, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    April 19, 2002. Case number: 15 300 00838 0. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 3: Hancock Teachers' Association and Hancock Central School District, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    May 2, 2002. Case number: 15 390 0034 1. Opinion and Award regarding salary rates.
  - Item 4: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    July 16, 2002. Case number: 15 672 00336 021. Opinion and Award regarding termination, suspension.
  - Item 5: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    July 16, 2002. Case number: 15 672 00336 02. Memorandum of Decision regarding termination, suspension.
  - Item 6: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    July 16, 2002. Case number: 15 672 00336 02. Memorandum of Decision regarding termination, suspension. Copy 2.
  - Item 7: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    October 17, 2002. Case number: 15 672 00336 02. Order regarding termination.
  - Item 8: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    November 30, 2002. Case number: 15 672 00639 02. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 9: State of New York, Department of Health and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 4)
    December 20, 2002. Case number: 15 672 00767 1. Opinion and Award regarding termination, suspension.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: State of New York, NYS Office of Mental Health and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    January 23, 2003. Case number: 13 672 01480 03. Opinion and Award regarding suspension.
  - Item 2: Champlain Valley Physicians Hospital Medical Center and Licensed Practical Nurses and Health Care Workers of New York, Local 721, SEIU, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    February 13, 2003. Case number: 15 300 00176 02. Opinion and Award regarding promotion.
  - Item 3: State of New York, State University of New York and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    April 25, 2003. Case number: 15 672 00167 03. Decision and Award regarding termination, suspension.
  - Item 4: Ellis Hospital and New York State Nurses Association, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    June 16, 2003. Case number: 15 300 00694 02. Consent Award regarding termination.
  - Item 5: Community General Hospital and Service Employees International Union (SEIU) Local 1199 Upstate., 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    June 18, 2003. Case number: 15 300 00635 02. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 6: Council 66, Local 400, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) and City of Syracuse New York, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    July 2, 2003. Case number: 15 390 00067 03. Opinion and Award regarding street repair.
  - Item 7: Von Roll Isola USA and International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Salaried, Machine and Furniture Workers Local 301, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    November 3, 2003. Case number: 15 300 00059 02. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
  - Item 8: State of New York, State University of New York and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    December 11, 2003. Case number: 15 672 00167 03. Opinion and Final Award regarding suspension.
  - Item 9: Dawson Metal Company and Local 439 Sheet Metal Production Workers, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 5)
    December 18, 2003. Case number: 15 300 00765 03. Decision and Award regarding lost wages.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Broome County and American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 6)
    February 7, 2004. Case number: 15 390 00658 03. Decision and Award regarding procedural issues.
  - Item 2: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and the Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 6)
    March 14, 2004. Case number: 15 672 00005 04. Opinion and Final Award regarding discharge.
  - Item 3: State of New York, Department of Correctional Services and the Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 6)
    July 20, 2004. Case number: 13 672 00535 04. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: New York State Tree Trimming and Line Clearing Contractors in Upper New York State North and West of the Westchester Line and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) Local 1249, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 7)
    January 3, 2005. Case number: 15 300 00300 03. Decision and Award regarding vacation pay credit.
  - Item 2: State of New YorK, Department of Transportation and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 7)
    January 13, 2005. Case number: 15 672 00377 04. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 3: State of New York, NYS Office of Mental Health and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 7)
    January 18, 2005. Case number: 15 672 00162 04. Opinion and Award regarding $260 fine.
  - Item 4: Broome County and Council 82, Local 2012, AFSCME, Security and Law Enforcement, 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 7)
    February 11, 2005. Case number: 15 390 00610 04. Opinion and Award regarding suspension.
  - Item 5: Strong Memorial Hospital and Local 1199 Upstate Service Employees International Union (SEIU), 2005; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 7)
    September 13, 2005. Case number: 15 300 00519 04. Opinion and Award regarding non-union worker.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2006; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: State of New YorK, Department of Transportation and The Public Employees Federation (PEF), 2006; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 8)
    June 3, 2006. Case number: 15 672 00377 04. Opinion and Decision regarding suspension.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: New York State Thruway Authority and Teamsters Local 72, New York State Thruway Employees, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 9)
    July 27, 2007. Case number: 15 390 00309 05. Opinion and Decision regarding "days off" scheduling.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Broome County and Council 82, Local 2012, AFSCME, Security and Law Enforcement, 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 10)
    January 1, 2008. Case number: 15 300 00481 07. Opinion and Decision regarding overtime pay.
  - Item 2: Saranac Lake Teachers' Association and Saranac Lake Central School District, 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 10)
    March 10, 2008. Case number: 15 390 00647 07. Opinion and Decision regarding non-union workers.
  - Item 3: Sodexho at Westchester Medical Center and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 10)
    April 5, 2008. Case number: 15 390 0768 07. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 4: Superintendent of the Duanesburg School and the Duanesburg Central School Teachers' Association, 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 10)
    December 1, 2008. Case number: 15 390 00885 07. Consent Award regarding health insurance benefits for part time employees.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Greater Amsterdam City School District and Amsterdam Teachers' Association, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 11)
    May 4, 2009. Case number: 15 390 00839 07 (2). Opinion and Decision regarding teacher preparation time.
  - Item 2: Broome County and Council 82, Local 2012, AFSCME, Security and Law Enforcement, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 11)
    May 19, 2009. Case number: 15 390 00387 08. Opinion and Decision regarding sick time use.
  - Item 3: First Group/First Student and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 11)
    June 1, 2009. Case number: 15 390 00188 08. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 4: Mechanicville City School District and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 11)
    November 15, 2009. Case number: 15 390 00332 09. Opinion and Decision regarding discipline.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2011; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Westchester County Healthcare and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2011; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 12)
    April 16, 2011. Case number: 15 390 00762 09. Opinion and Decision regarding out-of-title pay.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Columbia Memorial Hospital and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 13)
    February 15, 2012. Case number: 15 390 00286 11. Opinion and Decision regarding termination. Columbia Memorial Hospital also known as Katterskill Skilled Nursing Facility.
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Massena Memorial Hospital and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 14)
    May 11, 2013. Case number: 15 390 00827 12. Opinion and Decision regarding vacation scheduling.
  - Item 2: City of Cortland, NY, and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 14)
    June 1, 2013. Case number: 15 390 00581 12. Opinion and Decision regarding overtime.
  - Item 3: New York State Thruway Authority and Teamsters Local 72, New York State Thruway Employees, 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 14)
    July 28, 2013. Case number: 15 390 00426 07. Opinion and Decision regarding out-of-title work.
- Disciplinary Panel Administration, 1996-2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: State of New York, Institutional Services Unit and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 1996; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 15)
    February 5, 1996. Case number: 95 DIS 268. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 2: State of New York, Department of Taxation and Finance and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2001; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 15)
    May 28, 2001. Case number: 00 DIS 152. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 3: State of New York, Workers Compensation Board and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, 2002; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 15)
    May 2, 2002. Case number: 01 DIS 315. Opinion and Award regarding discharge.
  - Item 4: State of New York, Office of Mental Health and the Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, 2003; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 15)
    January 25, 2003. Case number: 02 DIS 231. Opinion and Award regarding discharge.
  - Item 5: State of New York, Deparment of Parks and Recreation and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, 2004; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 15)
    January 19, 2004. Case number: 03 DIS 162. Memorandum Decision Application to Modify regarding termination
  - Item 6: State of New York, Office of Children and Family Services and the Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2006; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 15)
    October 1, 2006. Case number 05 DIS 361. Opinion and Decision regarding $250 fine.
- Disciplinary Panel Administration, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: New York State Thruway Authority and Teamsters Local 72, New York State Thruway Employees, 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 16)
    April 18, 2007. Case: Section 75 Disciplinary Hearing. Opinion and Recommendation regarding suspended driver's license
  - Item 2: State of New York, Office of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities and the Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 16)
    August 13, 2007. Case number: 06 DIS 246. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 3: State of New York, Office of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities and the Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2007; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 16)
    November 11, 2007. Case number: 07 DIS 029. Opinion and Decision regarding termination, probable cause for suspension.
- Disciplinary Panel Administration, 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: State of New York, Department of State and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 17)
    March 23, 2008. Case number: 07 DIS 134. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 2: State of New York, Office of Mental Health and the Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2008; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 17)
    September 9, 2008. Case number: 07 DIS 323. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
- Disciplinary Panel Administration, 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: State of New York, Office of Children and Family Services and the Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 18)
    January 13, 2009. Case number: 08 DIS 219. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
  - Item 2: State of New York, Office of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities and the Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 18)
    October 6, 2009. Case number: 07 DIS 235. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
  - Item 3: State of New York, Office of Mental Retardation and Developmental Disabilities and the Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), 2009; Arbitration Case (Box 1, Folder 18)
    December 21, 2009. Case number: 09 DIS 030. Opinion and Decision regarding discharge.
- Disciplinary Panel Administration, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: State of New York, Office of People with Developmental Disabilities, Finger Lakes DDSO, and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 1)
    June 16, 2012. Case number: 11 DIS 336. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 2: State of New York, Office of Mental Health, Hudson River Psychiatric Center, and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 1)
    June 22, 2012. Case number: 11 DIS 039. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 3: State of New York, Office of Mental Health, Rockland Children's Psychiatric Center, and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 1)
    August 31, 2012. Case number: 11 DIS 853. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 4: State of New York, Office of People with Developmental Disabilities, Sunmont DDSO, and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 1)
    October 5, 2012. Case number: 11 DIS 778. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
  - Item 5: State of New York, Office of People with Developmental Disabilities, Sunmont DDSO, and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2012; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 1)
    October 5, 2012. Case number: 11 DIS 778. Opinion and Decision regarding termination. Copy 2.
- Disciplinary Panel Administration, 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: State of New York, Office of People with Developmental Disabilities, Sunmont DDSO, and Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA), Local 1000, AFSCME, 2013; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 2)
    August 13, 2013. Case number: 12 DIS 1083. Opinion and Decision regarding termination.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Renold Inc. and Lodge 1555, International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, 1984; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 3)
    April 20, 1984. Case number: 83K/27280. Opinion and Award regarding vacation pay proration.
  - Item 2: Letterkenny Army Depot and National Federation of Federal Employees (NFFE), Local 1429, 1988; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 3)
    August 17, 1988. Case number: 88-03839. Opinion and Award regarding suspension.
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: University of Rochester and International Union of Operating Engineers, Local 71-71A, 1991; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 4)
    April 15, 1991. Case number: 91-04745. Opinion and Award regarding termination.
  - Item 2: Allegany County Commissioners and the Allegany County Sheriff and Local 1521, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), 1992; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 4)
    February 8, 1992. Case number: 91-22278. Opinion and Award regarding suspension.
  - Item 3: Department of Defense Dependents School and Overseas Education Association, 1992; Arbitration Case (Box 2, Folder 4)
    August 17, 1992. Case number: 92-03625. Opinion and Award regarding living quarters allowance.